Inventory of the Keith E. Eiler papers, 1880-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
- Albert C. Wedemeyer file (Folder 2-16)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 11-16)
    - Mao, Paul Cheng-tzu, 1989 (Folder 16: 19)
    - Marshall, George C., 1951-1987 (Folder 16: 20-21)
    - Marshall, S. L. A., 1966 (Folder 16: 22)
    - Mason, Frank E., 1952-1977 (Folder 16: 23)
    - Meyer, Betty L., 1980-1981 (Folder 16: 24)
    - Millar, Russell W., 1987 (Folder 16: 25)
    - Millen, Jonathan A., II, 1985 (Folder 16: 26)
    - Miller, Luther D., 1987-1990 (Folder 16: 27)
    - Moley, Raymond, 1963 (Folder 16: 28)
    - Moore, Merrill, 1956-1986 (Folder 16: 29)
    - Moorer, Thomas H., 1974 (Folder 16: 30)
    - Moreell, Ben, 1941-1968 (Folder 16: 31)
    - Morley, Felix, 1960-1964 (Folder 16: 32)
    - Mosley, Leonard, 1982-1986 (Folder 16: 33)
    - Mountbatten, Louis, 1982-1986 (Folder 16: 34)
    - Nason, Mona, 1949-1987 (Folder 16: 35)
    - Neils, Patricia, 1988 (Folder 16: 36)
    - Nelson, Donald H., 1986 (Folder 16: 37)
    - Nixon, Richard, 1950-1975 (Folder 16: 38)
    - Norstad, Lauris, 1949-1987 (Folder 16: 39)
- Wedemeyer on War and Peace file (Folder 17-18)
  - Wedemeyer speeches and correspondence, 1950-1987 (Folder 17: 1)
  - Notes, drafts, and correspondence, 1960, 1985, undated (Folder 17: 2)
  - Introduction, annotated draft, 1985 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Correspondence and drafts, 1984-1987 (Folder 17: 4)
    Includes correspondence between Eiler and Robert Hessen
  - Drafts, 1985-1986, undated (Folder 17: 5-7)
  - Book chapters, 1941-1947, circa 1980s (Folder 18: 1-2)
- Albert C. Wedemeyer file (Folder 18)
  - Subject file (Folder 18)
    - Marshall Mission, 1978-1990 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Dixie Mission, 1991-1992 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Mission (1947), 1969-1986 (Folder 18: 5)
- Wedemeyer on War and Peace file (Folder 18-20)
  - Book chapters (Folder 18)
    - 1941-1947, circa 1980s (Folder 18: 6-27)
    - "Maturing of the Strategist,", 1947-1948, undated (Folder 18: 28-29)
      Includes original War College speeches and Wedemeyer correspondence
    - "Strategic Planning in the Post-War Army, 1947-49,", 1947-1985, undated (Folder 19: 1)
      Includes original declassified documents
  - "Report on China and Korea, 1947,", 1947, undated (Folder 19: 2)
  - Book chapters, 1949-1953, undated (Folder 19: 3-9)
  - Writings by Wedemeyer and research (Folder 19)
    - Author's forward on book on strategy and warfare, circa 1970s (Folder 19: 10)
      Most likely written by Wedemeyer
    - Collier's article by Wedemeyer, 1951 (Folder 19: 11)
    - Red China and the United Nations, circa 1950s (Folder 19: 12)
    - "Observations on Trip in Europe,", 1957 (Folder 19: 13)
    - Vietnam, 1964, undated (Folder 19: 14)
    - Relationship of Wedemeyer and George Marshall, undated (Folder 19: 15)
  - Research by year (Folder 19)
    Includes notes from 1980s
    - 1938-1942 (Folder 19: 16)
    - 1943 (Folder 19: 17)
    - 1944 (Folder 19: 18)
    - 1945 (Folder 19: 19)
    - 1946 (Folder 19: 20)
    - 1947 (Folder 19: 21)
  - China (1948), 1948-1987 (Folder 19: 22)
  - White paper on China, 1949 (Folder 19: 23)
  - Research by year (Folder 20)
    - 1950 (Folder 20: 1)
- Albert C. Wedemeyer file (Folder 20-30)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 20-21)
    - Duff family file, 1944-1996, undated (Folder 20: 2-12)
      Includes writings and correspondence of J. Arthur Duff, correspondence by Virginia Black, article by E. S. Little, and file on Mary Tyng Higgins and Tommy and Dorothy Lucy
    - Duff, J. Arthur, 1945-1988 (Folder 21: 1-2)
  - Subject file (Folder 21-23)
    - Marshall in China, 1996-1999, undated (Folder 21: 3-4)
    - Truman Library documents, 1947-1992 (Folder 21: 5)
    - Wedemeyer's policy folder and China research (1945-1946), 1943-1946 (Folder 22: 1)
    - China, 1945-1979 (Folder 22: 2-9)
    - China research (Folder 23)
      - China betrayed, 1947-1984 (Folder 23: 1)
      - U.S./China relations, 1945-1977, undated (Folder 23: 2)
      - Nationalist/Communist relations, 1945-1947, undated (Folder 23: 3)
      - White paper, 1949 (Folder 23: 4)
      - China lobby, 1951-1995 (Folder 23: 5)
      - China aid, 1946-1949 (Folder 23: 6)
      - Articles, 1969 (Folder 23: 7)
    - 1983 (Folder 23: 8)
    - 1951-1997 (Folder 23: 9)
  - General (Folder 23)
    - Missouri Valley History Conference (1983), 1946-1983 (Folder 23: 10)
      Eiler attended the conference with Wedemeyer, where both were commentators for the session "Second Front in Europe, 1942-1943"
  - Subject file (Folder 23-27)
    - China research (Folder 23)
      - Office of Strategic Services (OSS) and China, 1943-1997 (Folder 23: 11)
    - Pearl Harbor, 1962-2003 (Folder 24: 1)
    - Politics, 1976 (Folder 24: 2)
    - Psychological warfare, 1976 (Folder 24: 3)
    - Quebec, 1988 (Folder 24: 4)
    - Revisionism, 1959-1998 (Folder 24: 5)
    - Sino-American Cooperative Organization (SACO), 1946-1985 (Folder 24: 6)
    - Second Front, 1966-1989, undated (Folder 24: 7)
    - Operation Sledgehammer, 1982, undated (Folder 24: 8)
    - South East Asia Command (SEAC), 1943-1991 (Folder 24: 9)
    - Strategy, 1949-1993 (Folder 24: 10)
    - Strategy policy group, undated (Folder 24: 11)
    - Statecraft (U.S.), 1965-1983 (Folder 24: 12)
    - Strategy council, 1970-1985 (Folder 25: 1)
    - Summit conferences, 1969 (Folder 25: 2)
    - Ultra, 1978-1988 (Folder 25: 3)
    - Unconditional surrender, 1955-1958, undated (Folder 25: 4)
    - United Nations, 1954-1976 (Folder 25: 5)
    - Victory Plan, 1941-1994 (Folder 25: 6)
      Includes draft of Wedemeyer on War and Peace chapter. Includes original military documents, including a general summary plan for ground forces
    - Vietnam, 1967-2003 (Folder 25: 7)
    - West Point, 1960-1983 (Folder 25: 8)
    - World government, 1951 (Folder 25: 9)
    - World War II, 1939-1995 (Folder 25: 10)
    - Yalta, 1948-1969 (Folder 25: 11)
    - Yenan, 1995 (Folder 25: 12)
    - Young Americans for Freedom (YAF), 1960 (Folder 25: 13)
    - Presidential campaign of 1952 (Robert Taft and Dwight Eisenhower) (Folder 26: 1)
    - Presidential politics (Folder 26)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1955-1956 (Folder 26: 2)
      - Goldwater, Barry, 1964-1965 (Folder 26: 3)
      - Nixon, Richard, 1957-1976 (Folder 26: 4)
      - Ford, Gerald, 1975-1977 (Folder 26: 5)
      - Reagan, Ronald, 1979-1980 (Folder 26: 6)
    - Avco and Rheem, 1955-1975 (Folder 26: 7)
    - Wedemeyer on world affairs (Folder 26-27)
      - 1947-1949 (Folder 26: 8)
      - 1949-1959 (Folder 26: 9)
      - 1960-1969 (Folder 26: 10)
      - 1970-1979 (Folder 27: 1)
      - 1986, undated (Folder 27: 2)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 27)
    - Clausewitz, Carl von, 1940-1980 (Folder 27: 3)
  - Subject file (Folder 27)
    - Wedemeyer as fund raiser, 1961 (Folder 27: 4)
    - Wedemeyer as pacifist, 1979 (Folder 27: 5)
    - Wedemeyer on economics, 1963-1972 (Folder 27: 6)
    - Wedemeyer on history, 1965-1975 (Folder 27: 7)
    - Wedemeyer on labor, 1966-1976 (Folder 27: 8)
    - Wedemeyer on leadership, 1963 (Folder 27: 9)
    - Wedemeyer on liberalism, 1964-1966 (Folder 27: 10)
    - Wedemeyer on the media, 1964-1972 (Folder 27: 11)
    - Wedemeyer on military officers, 1961-1972 (Folder 27: 12)
    - Wedemeyer on politics, 1951-1978 (Folder 27: 13)
    - Wedemeyer on racism, 1969-1981 (Folder 27: 14)
    - Wedemeyer on U.S. global strategy, 1969-1980 (Folder 27: 15)
    - Wedemeyer on war, 1950-1960, undated (Folder 27: 16)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 27-29)
    - Taylor, Frank, 1960-1975 (Folder 27: 17)
    - Taylor, Harry J., 1962-1970 (Folder 27: 18)
    - Taylor, Maxwell, 1986-1987, undated (Folder 27: 19)
    - Thomas, Lowell, 1949-1979 (Folder 27: 20)
    - Thompson, John, 1989 (Folder 27: 21)
    - Thompson, Paul W., 1986 (Folder 27: 22)
    - Tolley, Kemp, 1986, undated (Folder 27: 23)
    - Tolstoy, Leo, 1962 (Folder 27: 24)
    - Tong, Hollington, 1955-1965 (Folder 27: 25)
    - Trohan, Walter, 1949-1974 (Folder 27: 26)
    - Trubey, Robert N., 1983 (Folder 27: 27)
    - Trudeau, Arthur G., 1955-1986 (Folder 27: 28)
    - Truman, Harry, 1964-1996 (Folder 27: 29)
    - Tuchman, Barbara, 1971-2003 (Folder 27: 30)
    - Tunner, William, undated (Folder 27: 31)
    - Twining, Nathan, 1953-1957 (Folder 27: 32)
    - Ungern, Reginald, 1945-1981, undated (Folder 27: 33)
    - United States Military Academy (USMA) at West Point classmates, 1980-1986 (Folder 27: 34)
    - Utley, Freda, 1951-1997 (Folder 28: 1)
    - Taft, Robert A., 1950-1999 (Folder 28: 2)
    - Tai-li, 1964-1965 (Folder 28: 3)
    - Valley, Bruce, 1985-1987 (Folder 28: 4)
    - Van Brunt, Winslow, 1961-1980 (Folder 28: 5)
    - Van Fleet, James, 1987 (Folder 28: 6)
    - Vance, John R., 1980-1986 (Folder 28: 7)
    - Vincent, John Carter, undated (Folder 28: 8)
    - Vittrup, Russell L., 1986-1991 (Folder 28: 9)
    - Vivas, Eliseo, 1961-1963 (Folder 28: 10)
    - Vladimirov, Peter, 1975-1977 (Folder 28: 11)
    - Von Helms, 1967-1980 (Folder 28: 12)
    - Von Plinsky, Alexander H., 1990-1994 (Folder 28: 13)
    - Wallace, George C., 1962-1973 (Folder 28: 14)
    - Wallace, Henry, 1951-1994 (Folder 28: 15)
    - Warren, Earl, 1950 (Folder 28: 16)
    - Wayne, John, 1952-1974 (Folder 28: 17)
    - Webber, Kenneth E., undated (Folder 28: 18)
    - Weems, Clarence N., 1988 (Folder 28: 19)
    - Welch, Robert, 1957-1967 (Folder 28: 20)
    - Welling, Arthur J., 1982-1991 (Folder 28: 21)
    - Wheeler, Burton K., 1962-1971 (Folder 28: 22)
    - Wheeler, Raymond A., 1949-1974 (Folder 28: 23)
    - White, Harry Dexter, 1968 (Folder 28: 24)
    - White, Theodore H., 1965-1986 (Folder 28: 25)
    - Wilbur, C. Martin, 1986 (Folder 28: 26)
    - Williams, J. C., 1980-1990 (Folder 28: 27)
    - Willoughby, Charles A., 1949-1972 (Folder 28: 28)
    - Wood, Sumner, 1964-1980 (Folder 28: 29)
    - Woodbury, John, 1980-1982 (Folder 28: 30)
    - Woolnough, James K., 1963-1992 (Folder 28: 31)
    - Yeaton, Ivan, 1971-1980 (Folder 29: 1)
    - Young, Jack T., 1988-1989 (Folder 29: 2)
    - Yutang, Lin, 1961 (Folder 29: 3)
  - General (Folder 29)
    - Photographic prints of presidents, undated (Folder 29: 4)
    - Speeches given by Wedemeyer at National War College, 1946-1957 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Subject file (Folder 29)
    - Stilwell notes, undated (Folder 29: 6)
  - General (Folder 29)
    - Research tasks, 1986, undated (Folder 29: 7)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 29)
    - Sunderland, Riley and Romanus, Charles F., 1954-1967 (Folder 29: 8)
  - General (Folder 29-30)
    - Wedemeyer Reports!, correspondence, reviews, and reactions, 1958-1971 (Folder 29: 9)
    - Writing Wedemeyer Reports!, 1956-1972 (Folder 30: 1)
  - Subject file (Folder 30)
    - Plans and operations (1947-1949), 1947-1986 (Folder 30: 2)
    - Planning (1941), 1941-2003 (Folder 30: 3)
    - Planning (1942), 1942-1969 (Folder 30: 4)
    - MacArthur hearing, 1951 (Folder 30: 5)
    - Stilwell, China-Burma-India Theater (CBI), and South East Asia Command (SEAC), 1944-1945 (Folder 30: 6)
    - South East Asia Command (SEAC), 1944-1946 (Folder 30: 7)
    - Axiom, 1944 (Folder 30: 8)
    - Korean War, 1949-1965 (Folder 30: 9)
    - Vietnam War, 1965-2002 (Folder 30: 10)
    - Office of Strategic Services (OSS) and China, 1945, undated (Folder 30: 11)
    - Japan, 1950-1968 (Folder 30: 12)
    - Second Army, 1946 (Folder 30: 13)
    - Sixth Army, 1950-1972 (Folder 30: 14)
    - Wartime air trips, 1944-1945 (Folder 30: 15)
- Sounds recordings and motion picture films (Folder 31)
  - Sound recordings (Folder 31)
    - Interview of Dr. Carroll Quigley, 1974 (Folder 31)
      One compact sound cassette
    - Tapes from the Department of the Army, Chief of Military History, and the Center of Military History, undated (Folder 31)
      Two compact sound cassettes
    - Unlabeled tape, undated (Folder 31)
    - Visit of Keith Eiler and General Yu Ta-wei, 1987 (Folder 31)
- Albert C. Wedemeyer file (Folder 31)
  - General (Folder 31)
    - Photographs and negatives (Folder 31)
      - Photograph of Wedemeyer (Oversize), undated (Folder 31)
      - Negative of quartermaster group (Oversize), undated (Folder 31)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 31)
    - Chiang Kai-shek (Oversize), 1945-1948 (Folder 31)
      Includes documents in Chinese. See also Box 8, folder 3.
- Note cards and card files (Folder 32-37)
  - Chronology of Wedemeyer's life, undated (Folder 32)
  - Individuals, organizations, and family (Wedemeyer), undated (Folder 33)
  - Topics (Wedemeyer), undated (Folder 34)
  - Bibliography by author and subject (Wedemeyer), undated (Folder 35)
  - Robert P. Patton bibliography and address file, undated (Folder 36)
  - Wedemeyer address file with comments, undated (Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous bibliography and address file, undated (Folder 36)
  - Wedemeyer bibliography and notes, undated (Folder 37)
    Includes comments on Wedemeyer Reports!
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1949
  - 2014 May release of records, 1949 (Box-folder 30: 16)
    Memorandum detailing meeting between Wedemeyer, C.H. Kan, and Leonard Hsu.